accela.com 2019-12-19

# Privacy Policy - Accela

## Accela, Inc. – Privacy Policy

#### Introduction

This Privacy Policy was updated on or about May 17, 2018. Accela, Inc. and its affiliated companies and subsidiaries (collectively referred to as “Accela,” “we,” or “us”) respect your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect Information from and about you, what we do with the Information, how we share it, and how we handle the content you place in our products and services. It also explains the choices available to you regarding use of your Personal Information. By providing Content, Information or Personal Information to us including on our website or purchasing our products or services, or signing an agreement that incorporates this Privacy Policy by reference you agree to this Privacy Policy.

#### Scope of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to the Information we obtain through your use of Accela’s products and services or visitation to Accela websites where this Privacy Policy is posted. It does not apply to any other Information collected by Accela through other means. If you have agreements with Accela for Accela products and services, then those agreements control to the extent of any conflict. Further, this Privacy Policy does not cover the activities of third parties except as specifically stated.

#### Definitions

_Content:_

any Information or data that you upload, submit, post, create, transmit, store or display in an Accela product or service. 

_Downloadable Products:_

Accela’s downloadable software products and mobile applications, including bundles of code, resources, and configuration files that can be used with an Accela product to add new functionality (including product version upgrades) created by Accela that are installed by customers on a device of their choice. 

_Information:_

all forms of data, content, and information collected by us. 

_Personal Information:_

Information that may be used to readily identify or contact you as an individual person, such as: name, address, email address or phone number. Personal Information does not include Information that has been anonymized such that it does not allow for the ready identification of specific individuals.

#### Our Collection of Personal Information

Accela collects Personal Information from you at several different points, including but not limited to the following: when we correspond with you as a customer or prospective customer; when you use our products or services; when you visit, register, or otherwise provide us your Personal Information on our website; when you contact us for help; when you interact with our advertising and marketing content; and when you participate at our conferences, attend our webinars, or visit our tradeshow booths. In using our products or services or requesting Information, you may provide a password for your account, your real name, industry, agency name, job role and contact Information. We may also collect other information including but not limited to the specific Accela product or service being used, the associated license identifier and domain name, the username and IP address or the individual using the product or service function; your credit card number and billing address when purchasing an Accela product or service; analytics Information including aggregated usage data; and other additional Information required to detail the operation of the Accela product or service.

#### Our Use of Your Information and Personal Information

Accela may use your Information and Personal Information to:

  * Deliver the products and services that you have requested, including software updates.
  * Manage your customer relationship and provide you with customer support.
  * Perform research and analysis about our customers’ use of, or interest in, our products, services or content.
  * Operate and improve our internal operations, systems, products and services including benchmarking system performance.
  * Understand you and your preferences to enhance your experience.
  * Respond to your comments and questions, and provide customer service.
  * Send you service-related information, including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages.
  * Deliver marketing communications.
  * Enforce our terms and conditions.
  * Recruit, onboard, and distribute payroll and benefits.
  * Communicate with you about products or services that may be of interest to you.

#### Our Disclosure of Your Personal Information to Third Parties

We may share your Personal Information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy:

  * When we have your permission, including when you choose to share Personal Information including using Accela Community or post to our blogs.
  * We may provide your Personal Information to our agents, partners, contractors, vendors or service providers who perform functions on our behalf.
  * We may share your information with our current or future “affiliates” (which means a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control), in which case we will require our affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.
  * We may disclose Personal Information to comply with laws or in response to legal process, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may disclose Personal Information in response to a law enforcement agency’s request, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, verify, prevent, enforce compliance with, or take action regarding: illegal or suspected illegal activities; suspected fraud; situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person; protection of the rights and property of Accela, our agents, customers or others; or violations or suspected violations of our agreements, policies or end user license agreements; or as otherwise required or permitted by law, or consistent with legal requirements. We reserve the right to transfer or disclose Personal Information in our system relating to or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, transaction or other proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture or assignment of all or a portion of our business or assets to a different entity.
  * Finally, we may also share aggregated, anonymized or statistical information about you, including demographics data, with others for a variety of purposes, including for their own uses, for example, for improving their products and services for Accela and others.

#### Our Security Measures to Protect your Personal Information

We have put in place reasonable and appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures in an effort to help safeguard Personal Information we collect. However, Accela cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information. To help protect yourself, please use a strong password, do not use the same passwords you use with other accounts or services, and protect your usernames and passwords.

#### End Customer Data

Accela’s customer may electronically submit Information to the product or service for processing and storage purposes (“End Customer Data”). We may access or process End Customer Data only for the purpose of providing the product or service or preventing or addressing service or technical problems or as may be required by law. If your Personal Information has been submitted to us by an Accela customer and you wish to exercise any rights you may have to access, correct, amend, or delete such data, please inquire with the relevant customer directly. Since Accela personnel have limited ability to access Information our customers submit to our products or services, if you wish to make your request directly to Accela, please provide the name of the Accela customer who submitted your data to our product or service. We will refer your request to that customer.

#### Our Retention of your Personal Information

Personal Information will be retained as long as needed to fulfill legitimate business purposes for which it was collected, including the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, or for a period of time specifically required or allowed by applicable regulations or laws. We will also retain and use your Personal Information for as long as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

#### Cookies/Web Beacons

When you use our websites, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies from our servers. If you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of our websites. Cookie management tools provided by your browser may not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies, go to: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118> (or in the EU YourOnlineChoices.com). You can also choose to opt-out of use of cookies by many of our third party advertising partners for delivery of personalized ads by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance (<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>) in the USA, Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada (<http://youradchoices.ca/>) in Canada or the European Digital Advertising Alliance (<http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>) in Europe. While we and others give you certain choices, as further outlined in this Privacy Policy, there are many ways that web browser signals and similar mechanisms can indicate your choice to disable tracking, and we may not be aware of nor honor every mechanism.

#### International Storage and Transfer of your Personal Information

Accela is a global company with affiliates, various business processes, management structures and technical systems that cross borders. Information collected by Accela or on behalf of may be stored on our computers, on our mobile devises, or on our servers, and may be transferred to, accessed from, or stored and processed in the United States and other counties including but not limited to Ireland, United Arab Emirates, Australia, New Zealand, Canada and any other country where Accela or its service providers maintain facilities or support centers.

#### Your Access to and Amendment of your Personal Information

Our marketing emails tell you how to “opt-out” of receiving further marketing emails. If you opt out, we may still send you non-marketing emails including emails about your accounts and our business dealings with you. We allow you to access your Personal Information (with proper identification verification), and allow you to correct, amend or delete inaccurate Personal Information, except where the burden or expense of providing such an access is disproportionate to the individual privacy risk, or where the rights of persons other than the requesting individual risk being violated. This information request can be made by sending an email to legal@accela.com.

#### Children’s Privacy

Because of the nature of our business, our services are not designed to appeal to minors. We do not knowingly attempt to solicit or receive any information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with Personal Information, please contact us immediately.

#### Changes to This Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may collect and use Personal Information in ways not previously disclosed in our Privacy Policy. If our information practices or this policy change, we will post adjustments to this policy and change the “Last Updated” date. Unless additional notice or consent is required by applicable laws, this will serve as your notification of these changes.

#### Contacting Us

If you have questions or suggestions, please email Accela at [legal@accela.com](mailto:legal@accela.com). Please send all written communication to: Accela, Inc. Attn: General Counsel 2633 Camino Ramon, Suite 500 Bishop Ranch 3 San Ramon, California 94583, United States
